export const BUSINESSMANAGEMENTA2014 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The factors of production that organizes other factors of production is",
A: "Labour",
B: "Land",
C: "Entrepreneur",
D: "Capital",
answer: "C. Entrepreneur",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Sand winning is an example of",
A: "Manufacturing industry",
B: "Extractive industry",
C: "Direct service",
D: "Construction industry",
answer: "B. Extractive industry",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The tendency for firms and individuals to concentrate their efforts on a particular productive activity is known as",
A: "Specialization",
B: "Commercialization",
C: "Rationalization",
D: "Nationalization",
answer: "A. Specialization",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Separate legal entity is a feature of",
A: "Partnership",
B: "Public corporation",
C: "Public company",
D: "Sole proprietorship",
answer: "C. Public company",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following organisations has the least number of membership?",
A: "Public limited liability",
B: "Partnership",
C: "Co-operative society",
D: "Sole proprietorship",
answer: "D. Sole proprietorship",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following is a statutory organisation?",
A: "Cooperative society",
B: "Public corporation",
C: "Public company",
D: "Partnership",
answer: "B. Public corporation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of following organizations shares profits to its members based on their rates of patronage with the organisation?",
A: "Partnership",
B: "Private company",
C: "Public corporation",
D: "Cooperative Society",
answer: "D. Co-operative society",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Shares with fixed annual quoted dividend are",
A: "Preference shares",
B: "Ordinary share",
C: "Founders shares",
D: "Participating shares",
answer: "A. Preference shares",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. One characteristic of a co-operative society is that",
A: "It is owned arid managed by the members who form it",
B: "The administration of the society is in the hands of the employees",
C: "Voting power of members depends on the number of shares held.",
D: "The death of a member means the end of the society",
answer: "A. It is owned and managed by the members who form it",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The process of interpreting a message by the receiver is known as",
A: "Transmission",
B: "Receiving",
C: "Encoding",
D: "Decoding",
answer: "D. Decoding",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Communication without any feedback is",
A: "One-way communication",
B: "Two-way communication",
C: "Formal communication",
D: "lnformal communication",
answer: "A. One—way communication",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The directional flow of communication is referred to as",
A: "Grapevine",
B: "lnformal",
C: "Channel",
D: "Formal",
answer: "C. Channel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A type of decision that is repetitive and virtually automatic is known as",
A: "Unprogrammed decision",
B: "Programmed decision",
C: "Non-routine decision",
D: "Strategic decision",
answer: "B. Programmed decision",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following types of decision greatly affects the entire organisation?",
A: "Tactical decision",
B: "Operating decision",
C: "Strategic decision",
D: "Constant decision",
answer: "C. Strategic decision",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The last step in decision-making process is",
A: "Establishing objectives",
B: "Revision of the decision",
C: "Evaluating alternatives",
D: "Gathering of information",
answer: "B. Revision of the decision",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A contract is sometimes referred to as an",
A: "Executed consideration",
B: "Invitation to treat",
C: "Executor consideration",
D: "Enforceable agreement",
answer: "D. Enforceable agreement.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following does not terminate an offer",
A: "Acceptance",
B: "Rejection",
C: "Counter offer",
D: "Lapse of time",
answer: "A. Acceptance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A minor can enter a contract to buy",
A: "Textbooks",
B: "Cigarettes",
C: "Liquor",
D: "Tractor",
answer: "A. textbooks",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. In a contract of sale of goods, property means the",
A: "Goods are for sale",
B: "Ownership to the goods",
C: "Goods that have been sold on credit",
D: "Goods sold on hire purchase",
answer: "B. Ownership to the goods",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The responsibility of business to its employees is the prompt payment of",
A: "Taxes",
B: "Dividend",
C: "Membership dues",
D: "Wages and salaries",
answer: "D. Wages and salaries",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following stakeholders bargain on behalf of employees",
A: "Board of directors",
B: "Creditors",
C: "Government",
D: "Labour unions",
answer: "D. Labour unions",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Increase in capital gains is the primary interest of",
A: "investors",
B: "suppliers",
C: "competitors",
D: "government",
answer: "A. investors",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. An example of indirect tax is",
A: "Goods and services tax",
B: "Poll tax",
C: "Company income tax",
D: "Personal income tax",
answer: "A. Goods and services tax",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The period during which a business organization is free of taxation is referred to as",
A: "Tax rebate",
B: "Tax holiday",
C: "Income tax",
D: "Tax incentive",
answer: "B. Tax holiday",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Taxes imposed on property is an example of",
A: "Proportional tax",
B: "Indirect tax",
C: "Income tax",
D: "Direct tax",
answer: "D. Direct tax",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following activities can be used by the central bank to control inflation?",
A: "Issuing of currency notes",
B: "Buying securities",
C: "Sale of securities",
D: "Reducing bank rate",
answer: "D. Reducing bank rate",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. One of the functions of commercial banks is",
A: "Controlling monetary and fiscal policies",
B: "Issuing of currency notes",
C: "Discounting of bills of exchange",
D: "Acting as a lender of last resort",
answer: "C. Discounting of bills of exchange",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Doris insured her car against fire. When the somersaulted, she presented a claim to the insurance company and the insurance company refused to pay her. The action by the insurer is line with the principle of",
A: "Indemnity",
B: "Proximate cause",
C: "Insurable interest",
D: "Utmost good faith",
answer: "B. Proximate cause",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The principle of insurance with authorizes the insurance company to possess the residual value of the risk insured against is",
A: "Subrogation",
B: "Indemnity",
C: "Insurable interest",
D: "Proximate cause",
answer: "C. Insurable interest",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Stock exchange is a",
A: "Money market",
B: "Foreign exchange market",
C: "Parallel market",
D: "Capital marker",
answer: "D. Capital market",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The relationship between the prices of a nation’s exports and its imports shows",
A: "Exchange rate",
B: "Balance of accounts",
C: "Balance of payments",
D: "Terms of trade",
answer: "D. Terms of trade",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. When goods are sold to another country at prices cheaper than its country of origin, it is termed as",
A: "inflation",
B: "Investment",
C: "Deflation",
D: "Dumping",
answer: "D. Dumping",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Most of the economies in West Africa are characterized by",
A: "High dependence on a single export product",
B: "High standard of living",
C: "Surplus balance of payments",
D: "High level of skilled man power",
answer: "A. High dependence on a single export product.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The International Bank for Reconstruction and Development is also called",
A: "World Rank",
B: "European Bank",
C: "lnternational Monetary Fund",
D: "African Development Bank",
answer: "A. World Bank",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following is not an economic grouping?",
A: "Economic Community of West African States",
B: "European Union",
C: "African Caribbean and Pacific",
D: "World Health Organisation",
answer: "D. World Health Organisation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following is not an input device of a computer?",
A: "Mouse",
B: "Monitor",
C: "Touch pad",
D: "Keyboard",
answer: "B. Monitor",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. An electronic device used to store, process and retrieve information is a",
A: "Computer",
B: "Modem",
C: "Pen drive",
D: "Printer",
answer: "A. Computer",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. A manager who is responsible for the daily supervision of workers is a",
A: "First-line manager",
B: "Middle level manager",
C: "Top level manager",
D: "Chief executive officer",
answer: "A. First-Line manager",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The principle of organization which regulates the maximum number of subordinates reporting to a superior is",
A: "Span or control",
B: "Delegation",
C: "Unity of objectives",
D: "Unity of command",
answer: "A. Span or control",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following factors does not determine the location of a business? The availability of",
A: "Raw materials",
B: "Labour",
C: "Capital",
D: "Machines",
answer: "C. Capital.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. One of the functions of an organisation chart is that it",
A: "Depicts the total number of workers in, an organisation",
B: "Shows the structure of an organisation at a glance",
C: "Shows the location of an organisation",
D: "Shows the salary structure of the organisation",
answer: "B. Shows the structure of an organisation at a glance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. An industrial action in which employers force workers not to be on the work premises is",
A: "Boycott",
B: "Picketing",
C: "Lock-out",
D: "Arbitration",
answer: "C. Lock—out.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. A situation whereby an employee is moved from one organisational location to another is referred to as",
A: "Promotion",
B: "Demotion",
C: "Transfer",
D: "Termination",
answer: "C. Transfer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Job analysis comprises of",
A: "Job evaluation and job description",
B: "Job specification and job description",
C: "Job description and job enlargement",
D: "Job specification and job evaluation",
answer: "B. job specification and job description",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Setting a high price for a product at its introduction stage is referred to as",
A: "Loss leader pricing",
B: "Psychological pricing",
C: "Skimming pricing",
D: "Penetration pricing",
answer: "C. Skimming pricing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The process by which a company distinguishes its products through packaging, branding and colour is referred to as",
A: "Marker differentiation",
B: "Product mix",
C: "Produce differentiation",
D: "Marketing mix",
answer: "C. Product differentiation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the following marketing functions changes the title of ownership for commodity?",
A: "Distribution",
B: "Advertising",
C: "Selling",
D: "Production",
answer: "C. Selling",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following sources is an internal means of finance to a business?",
A: "Debenture",
B: "Leasing",
C: "Trade credit",
D: "Sales of assets",
answer: "D. Sales of assets",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. 0ne advantage of Pay-As-You-Earn (PAYE) tax is that it",
A: "Protects infant industries",
B: "ls not difficult to evade",
C: "ls difficult to evade",
D: "Attracts no administrative cost",
answer: "C. Is difficult to evade",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The principle of taxation that does not allow for discrimination is",
A: "Certainty",
B: "Equity",
C: "Convenience",
D: "Economy",
answer: "B. Equity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]